# Krishan Samarawickrama

#### Tech Enthusiast I Mentor

A versatile individual with nearly a decade of experience in working on a variety of projects from conception to delivery. Excellent understanding and professions of platforms for effective software development. Including C# .net, SQL, Angular, R and Power BI. In recent years I have been more interested in data analytics and recently completed the Google data analytics certificate.



Krishan.Samarawickrama@outlook.com

Mount Lavinia, Sri Lanka

+94 77 824 9689

in linkedin.com/in/krishan-samarawickrama

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Senior Software Engineer (Full Stack)

Data Capture Experts

01/2020 - Present

# **Senior Software Engineer**

Softlogic Holdings PLC

04/2016 - 01/2020

# **Software Developer**

QB Lanka (Pvt) Ltd

01/2015 - 04/2016

### **Software Developer**

**Dexter Business Solutions** 

03/2013 - 04/2014

### **PROJECTS**

#### DC2Vue Connect (2021 - Present)

- Designed and implemented Biometric Identity Verification using Azure cognitive services.
- Guided and mentored team members (technical) to achieve the target deadlines.

#### DC2Vue (2020 - Present)

- Designed and developed a reporting module for DC2Vue platform which includes Power BI embedded reports and XML reports for Australian government agencies.
- Designed and developed notification(Email, SMS) management module for DC2Vue platform.

#### Softlogic Insurance Claiming Integration (2019 - 2020)

 Implemented an insurance claims process automation system between Softlogic LifeInsurance and Asiri Hospitals.

#### Softlogic Petty Cash System (2018 - 2019)

 Initially, it was a personal project that evolved into a petty cash management system that integrated with Oracle Enterprise-wide Accounting.

#### RetailRx (2017 - 2019)

- Developed an Inventory control and Point of Sales System for Asiri Hospitals Pharmacy.
- Implemented a reporting framework using crystal reports.

#### Asiri Hospital Management System (2016 - 2017)

Developed a Ward Management System for Asiri Hospitals.

#### QBL ERP (2015 - 2016)

- Collaborated in re engineering the QBL ERP system.
- Customized and deployed the QBL ERP system to more that 10 customers.
- Developed a Loan Module for Sri Lanka Insurance Thrift Society

#### DBS Attendance System (2013 - 2014)

- Built an Attendance Management System and synchronized data from fingerprint devices via the network.
- Analyze user needs and software requirements to determine the feasibility of design within time and cost constraints.

# **SKILLS**



# **EDUCATION**

### **PGDip Big Data Analytics**

Robert Gordon University

2016 - 2017

# BSc Computer Science

University College Dublin

2011 - 2014

### **CERTIFICATES**

Google Data Analytics by Google on Coursera (2021)

# **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

### Program Manager, Volunteer

International Movement for Community Development (IMCD)

2014 - 2017

Tasks/Achievements

 Organized several seasonal events to entertain people who stays at residential care (Amuzed Project)

# Volunteer Manager

Infotel ICT Expo

10/2014 - 11/2014
Tasks/Achievements

Organized Infotel ICT Expo 2014

# **INTERESTS**

.Net Cloud Computing

Data Science